♪ Men. ♪
Yeah, I gotta tell ya,
my brother does basically
the same thing
in the shower every day
and he has absolutely
no muscle tone in his arms.
All right, I'm out of here.
Hold on a sec.
What does this look
like to you, Berta?
Your brother in the shower?
You hear that?
It's not just me.
Thanks, Berta.
I'll see you tomorrow.
No, you won't.
I told you, I'm going to a
family reunion for a few days.
But what about me?
All right,
let's go through this
one more time.
I arranged to have a friend
fill in for me.
Her name is Esmerelda.
I have given her
detailed instructions
about how you like things done
around here.
Did you tell her to roll me over
on my stomach
so I don't choke
on my own vomit?
That's number one on the list.
Is she hot?
She was in the '70s.
I guess it's better that way.
Yeah, it's tough enough that
you and I have sexual tension.
Oh, by the way, you
promised me vacation pay.
Okay.
How much did
we agree on?
That looks about right.
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
Uncle Charlie in there?
Yep.
Drunk?
Hammered.
You clean him out?
Would I do that
to my little buddy?
Thank you, Berta.
All right, have a good
weekend, Uncle Charlie.
Enjoy your family reunion.
What?
You know, you still owe me
for that pizza
from the other night.
Oh, yeah, sorry.
How much was it?
That'll do it.
Jake, let's go.
Your mom's outside.
See ya,
Uncle Charlie.
See ya, buddy.
Thanks for the pizza.
When did you guys have pizza?
I have no idea.
Hey, Charlie,
you remember Lyndsey?
Nope.
Hey, look.
(chuckles)
I'm exercising.
Oh, maybe you ought
to sit down for a minute.
Good idea.
I'm getting
a little dizzy.
I hope I don't have
a heart problem.
No, you have
a drinking problem.
That's a relief.
So who's this Lyndsey?
You remember-- Lyndsey,
early 40s, blonde, pretty.
No recollection.
I burned her house down.
She left me, went back
to her ex-husband?
Keep going.
Nice, full, very natural
looking C-cup?
Oh, right, Lyndsey.
Here we go.
What are you doing?
Child-proofing you.
Thank you.
So you're-you're dating
Lindsay Lohan?
No, no, Lyndsey MacElroy.
Anyway, she called
and apparently
things aren't working out
with the ex-husband,
and even though she
didn't exactly say she
wanted to get back together, I
am going to meet her for dinner.
Well, that's great.
Mm-hmm.
Good for you.
How do I look?
Like Lance Armstrong
after a three-day drunk.
Nice.
Mm-hmm.
You are a good brother, Alan.
Have some money.
Thanks.
If I were really
a good brother,
I would stage
an intervention.
Thanks for the pizza.
Eureka.
I've invented
the drinking helmet.
== Sync, corrected by elderman ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==
♪ Men, men, men, men, manly men,
men, men ♪
♪ Ah. ♪
♪ Men. ♪
♪ Two and a Half Men 8x09 ♪
A Good Time in Central Africa
Original Air Date on November 15, 2010
♪ Men. ♪
(sighs)
Hello?
(speaking Spanish)
Oh, man, did I go
to Tijuana last night?
Me... you...
Not married, are we?
I guess if the answer was yes,
she wouldn't be polishing
the piano.
Hey, Alan, quick question.
Yeah?
Who is that in
our living room?
That's Esmerelda.
Gonna need more.
Berta's friend?
Keep going.
Berta went
to her family reunion.
Esmerelda's filling in for her.
Oh. It would have been nice
if she'd given me a heads-up.
Aren't you going to ask me
about last night?
Oh, yeah.
What did I do last night?
Somehow I spent
almost all my money.
No, I meant
what I did last night.
Oh. No.
Lyndsey wants
to get back together.
C-cups.
Right. Lyndsey.
She did split up
with her ex-husband Chris.
Said she realized
she didn't want to go backwards.
In what universe is dating you
not going backwards?
I know. This guy must be
some kind of mess.
Breakfast, Señor Harper?
Why is she saying breakfast?
Am I supposed to make her
breakfast?
She'll make it for you.
Try the huevos rancheros--
they're amazing.
(speaking Spanish)
Muy bien.
Gracias.
Where did you learn
to speak Spanish?
Junior high, high school,
college,
two years of chiropractic school
in Mexico.
You say that like
I'm supposed to know.
You are supposed to know.
You're my brother.
(Esmerelda laughing)
What's so funny?
Are you talking about me?
She says she likes your hat.
♪ Men. ♪
CHARLIE:
Alan! Come here, quick!
Please God,
don't let it be a dead girl.
What is it?
Open my door and
tell me what you see.
Why? What do you see?
Just look.
Are the flying monkeys back?
Don't joke about that, Alan.
Wow.
Esmerelda did this?
Can you believe it?
The fresh cut flowers,
the carafe of lemon water.
She even laid out
my robe and slippers.
Since when
do you have slippers?
I don't know. Is it
possible she made them?
She put a chocolate on your pillow?
Yup.
See what it says?
"Felicidad."
That means
"Merry Christmas," right?
It means "happiness."
You sure? What about that song,
uh, "Felicidad Navidas"?
"Feliz Navidad"?
Tomato, tamale.
The point is,
Esmerelda is
a terrific housekeeper.
I didn't get
a chocolate.
You're not Señor Harper.
I'm a Señor Harper.
Yes, but not the Señor Harper
that pays her.
Come on, you got
to see this.
She still could have
given me a chocolate.
How much could it cost?
Look!
That's not a swan.
That's my towel.
Nice touch.
Had me fooled
at first.
I tried to kill it.
And look.
She folded my toilet paper
into a little point.
After breakfast,
I used some, stood up, shaved,
and when I looked back,
I swear it was pointed again.
Is that a votive candle?
Yup.
She's praying that I have
pleasant bowel movements.
Oh, please.
No, no, no, it's working.
This morning, soft, firm,
easy peasy.
But wait, there's more.
Come on.
Tada!
She bought you a new grill?!
No, no, no, this
is the old grill.
You know what she did?
What?
She cleaned it.
She cleaned the grill?
Berta never cleans the grill.
Tell me about it.
She only comes out on the deck
to smoke pot.
Señor Harper?
Yes?
She's talking to me,
Baba Looey. Yes?
Hell, yeah, botanas.
What's that mean,
"screw you"?
Basically.
I love this woman.
Esmerelda, te amo.
Ay, Señor.
I thought you didn't
speak Spanish.
I don't, but I do know
how to say "I love you"
and "How much for
a happy ending?"
in, like, 17
different languages.
You're kidding.
(speaking foreign
language and clicking)
In case you ever want to have
a good time in Central Africa.
♪ Men. ♪
(doorbell ringing)
CHARLIE:
Alan, get that!
Esmerelda's giving
me a pedicure!
Pedicure. I can't even get
a freakin' chocolate.
Hello, Alan.
Chris! Hey.
Uh, what brings you by?
Well, Lyndsey mentioned
that you two are dating again,
and I wanted to let you know
that if I had to lose her,
I'm glad it was to you.
Thank you.
How did you get my address?
Not important.
Here, I brought you
a little gift.
Okay.
(chuckles)
Nothing in here's
gonna bite me, is it?
(chuckles)
Open it.
Oh.
Look at that.
It's a picture of
Lyndsey and you.
Yeah. Look how happy we were.
We just found out
she was pregnant.
It kind of looks like she's
glowing, but it's really just
the lights from the Ferris wheel
on the Santa Monica Pier.
I-I can't accept this.
Oh, I want you to have it.
You need to see
how happy Lyndsey made me,
so you can be that happy.
Okay, I'm not quite sure
I follow the logic,
um, but-but thank you.
See you around.
(clicks tongue)
Ah, it's too late, Alan.
You're already dead.
Well, that was a bit disturbing.
♪ Men. ♪
Okay, uh, one decaf
grande soy chai latte
with extra whipped cream.
Uh, and a black
coffee for the lady.
Thank you.
I don't know how you
drink that stuff.
Back at you.
Name?
Uh, Alan.
So, what's so important
that you didn't want
to talk about it
on the phone?
Oh, it's not that
it's important,
uh, it's just
that it's...
Alan, if you
dragged me down here
to break up with me,
I will murder you.
Oh, no, nobody's
breaking up.
But, uh, speaking
of murder,
I saw your
ex-husband yesterday.
I'm sorry, "speaking of murder"?
Oh, oh, maybe I should
back up a little.
Um, Chris showed up at
my house and handed me
what I consider to be a very
inappropriate photo of you two.
That bastard!
He told me he threw
those pictures away.
Okay, I-I don't think we're
talking about the same pictures.
Uh, but the point is, before
he left, he shot at me.
He shot at you?
Oh, not with a gun,
with his finger.
But the implication
was pretty darn clear.
Okay, let me
get this straight.
I wasn't naked
in the picture?
No, you were at the
Santa Monica Pier.
But not naked, right?
Right.
Uh, but again,
my concern here
is that your ex-husband
seems to be threatening me.
Oh, Chris is harmless.
His bark is way worse
than his bite.
So you're saying
he does bite?
Alan, you have nothing
to worry about.
And if it'll make you
feel better,
I'll talk to Chris
next time I see him.
Talk to me about what?
What the hell?!
How long have you
been sitting there?
I just got here.
I was gonna come say hi,
but I thought
it was a little creepy--
ex-husband, new boyfriend.
Are you following us?
No. I just stopped in
to have a cup of coffee.
You live on
the other side of town.
But I like the coffee here.
Okay, I don't know what
you're trying to accomplish,
but it needs to stop right now.
Uh, I've got
this, Lyndsey.
Now... listen up, pal.
I'm dating your ex-wife,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
Do you understand me?
(shrieks):
Police! Police!
Whoa.
Calm down.
Chris, get
out of here.
I'm leaving.
Oh, Alan.
What?
See you around.
See? See?
He shot me again!
Calm down.
Calm down?!
This guy is crazy.
We need get a restraining order
or something.
I don't think
that's necessary.
Of course it's necessary.
This is unacceptable behavior,
and I am not putting up with it.
In fact,
forget the restraining order.
I'm gonna pay him a visit
and make it crystal clear
that he is messing with
the wrong guy.
Alan!
(shrieks):
Police! Police!
♪ Men. ♪
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
Breakfast time.
Esmerelda's huevos rancher...
Oh, Berta!
Hey.
I thought you were
at a family reunion.
Came home early.
Turns out,
I don't like my family.
So you came back.
Yay.
So Esmerelda's not
coming in anymore?
No, I called her.
She didn't mess things up
too bad, did she?
No, no, no.
I mean, she's not you,
so there was
a little adjustment.
What's that
you're eating?
Western omelette.
Oh. Looks good.
It is.
Which reminds me,
you're out of eggs.
(door opens, closes)
ALAN:
Charlie?
In here.
Staring at me while I eat
is making me
very uncomfortable.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Charlie, I've got
a problem.
How about that,
the problem's got a problem.
Berta's back.
Yay.
I'm going somewhere
I can eat in peace.
I thought my family
was annoying.
Can you believe it?
Esmerelda's gone.
Yeah, boo-hoo.
Lyndsey's ex-husband
threatened to kill me.
How is that a bigger problem
than me having to make
my own breakfast?
I'm serious, Charlie.
He's crazy.
Well, of course
he's crazy.
He's an ex-husband.
The two words
go together.
"Crazy ex-husband."
I'm an ex-husband.
There you go.
Now, what are we gonna
do about Esmerelda?
I mean, it's not like
I can fire Berta.
Sure you can. Frankly,
I never cared for the woman.
What am I gonna do
about Chris?
I don't want to lose Lyndsey;
I love her.
And I love
huevos rancheros
and chocolate "felicidadas"
on my pillow.
Okay, we seem to be talking
at cross purposes here.
'Cause you're not focusing
on the real issue.
I've just lost the best
housekeeper since...
Wilma Flintstone.
(screams)
What the hell?
What was that?
A rock.
It's got to be Chris.
How can you be sure?
Who else would
throw a rock at me?
Good point. I'm here
and Mom's out of town.
I ain't cleaning that up.
♪ Men. ♪
(TV playing quietly)
(phone rings)
Hello.
Hello?
("Up, Up and Away"
ringtone playing)
Hello?
Hello?!
Okay, whoever this is,
you should know
that you're not scaring me.
(doorbell rings, Alan screams)
Esmerelda!
Come on in.
Buenas noches, Señor Harper.
Yeah, yeah, me, too.
Esmerelda?
Oh, como esta, Señor Alan?
Muy bien.
Charlie, what's going on?
Excusez-moi.
From now on, Berta will be
our day housekeeper
and Esmerelda will be
our night housekeeper.
Capiche?
Does Berta know?
Berta doesn't need to know.
Uh-huh. So what's she gonna
think when she comes back
and she sees the pointed toilet
paper and the swan towels?
Way ahead of you.
I'll just un-swan
and un-point everything
before she gets here.
Then why do it?
I mean, is it
worth the trouble
to sneak around
behind Berta's back?
I know it's crazy, but...
...the woman makes me happy.
Botanas, Señor Harper?
Oh, si... vous plaît.
How about that?
I'm even starting
to pick up the language.
It's a shame the
language is French.
(phone rings)
(screams)
♪ Men. ♪
Alan, relax.
If Chris wanted to kill you,
he'd just climb through your
window while you're sleeping
and smother you
with a pillow.
Thank you,
that's very helpful.
At least, that's how
I always imagined doing it.
BERTA:
You rat bastard.
Berta!
It's not what it looks like.
Is that so?
Then what is it?
Uh... it's purely sexual.
I'm not stupid, Charlie.
I know when I'm being two-timed.
Charlie, I'm shocked.
Shocked!
Berta, I-I had no idea
this was going...
Stay out of it, Zippy!
I'm out.
So what do you have to say
for yourself?
Berta, I am... I am so sorry.
I got carried away, but I think
if we all sit down like adults
and talk this through,
we can make it work.
Uh-uh.
It's either me or her.
Oh, please don't make me choose.
Berta, I love you both.
Good-bye, Charlie.
No, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
It's you, Berta.
It's always been you.
I'm sorry.
It's just not our time.
Please tell her how sorry I am.
(speaking Spanish)
(both laugh)
Adios, Señor Harper.
Arrivederci, Esmerelda.
Okay, then.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good, good.
I'll be late.
It's okay.
You might want to clean
that hair up off the floor
before I get in.
Sure, I'm on it.
Okay.
(sighs)
Oh, Esmerelda.
No.
No, I can't let her go.
Oh, hey, Chris.
Pillows on the couch, Alan's
in his room. Esmerelda!
== Sync, corrected by elderman ==
== for www.addic7ed.com ==